Inventory of the Crede H. Calhoun papers, 1907-2021
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Crede H. Calhoun papers
1907-2021
Calhoun, Crede H. (Crede Haskins), 1885-1978.
05607
4.31 cubic ft. (5 boxes) + 3.63 MB
University of Wyoming. American Heritage Center.
Papers of a journalist and Chief of Division for Civil Affairs and Director of Posts in the Panama Canal Zone from 1907 to the 1950s.
Biography of Crede H. Calhoun
Crede Haskins Calhoun (1885-1978) worked as Chief of Division for Civil Affairs and Director of Posts and as a journalist, in the Panama Canal Zone, from 1922-1947. He first came to the Panama Canal in 1907 to work as a postal clerk and after a brief return to the U.S. for college, he worked as a reporter for the Panama "Star & Herald" from 1911-1920, the New York "Herald Tribune" from 1920-1926 and the New York "Times" from 1926-1952. While with the "Times" Calhoun covered Central and South America and Charles Lindbergh's flight across Central America. After 1953 he wrote occasionally for "Newsweek" magazine.
Collection contains personal and professional correspondence (1931-1970); subject files on stories covered by Calhoun in Ecuador, Guatemala, Nicaragua and on the Pan-American Highway, the Panama Canal Zone and Charles Lindbergh (1931-1970); maps of Central and South America; 8 scrapbooks (1934-1947); and photographs of Charles Lindbergh, Albert Einstein, President Franklin D. Roosevelt, Calhoun, and the Panama Canal (1931-1947). Some of the materials are in Spanish.
There are no access restrictions on the materials for research purposes, and the collection is open to the public.
There are no known other archival collections created by Crede H. Calhoun at the date of processing.
Finding aid available in repository.
The collection material was received from Crede H. Calhoun in 1977; Rith Rickarby, 1974,1981; Brittmarie Perez from 2018-2022.
Access Terms
Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1902-1974.;; Journalism -- Panama.; Journalism -- Central America.; Pan American Highway System.; Panama Canal (Panama); Panama -- History -- 20th century.; Central America -- History.; Maps.; Photographs.; Journalists.
Arts, Humanities, and Social Sciences; Journalism
- Personal
  - Biographical Material; Photographs, 1915-1978 (Box 1 and digital, Folder ahcdm_05607_001)
- Correspondence
  - Correspondence - Personal, Professional, and Photographs, 1915-1974 (Box 1)
- Photographs
  - Animals; Sailors, undated (Box 1)
  - Albert Einstein and Wife; Franklin D. Roosevelt; Governor of the Panama Canal; Crede H. Calhoun, 1931 December, undated (Box 1)
  - Charles A. Lindbergh (Air Pilot, Canal Zone), 1929 (Box 1)
  - Military Reception; Plane; Crede H. Calhoun, 1946-1947 (Box 1)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt; Crede H. Calhoun; Press Conference; Plane; Ship, 1947, undated (Box 1)
  - Franklin D. Roosevelt; Military; Cabot Medal; Ships, 1934-1953, undated (Box 1)
  - Ships; Reception; Crede H. Calhoun and Others, 1946-1947 (Box 1)
- Subject Files
  - Army, 1941-1943 (Box 1)
  - Constitutions, 1939-1951 (Box 1)
  - Ecuador - General, 1930-1945 (Box 1)
  - End of Two Wars, 1919-1949 (Box 1)
  - Fact Sheet, 1977 August 15 (Box 1)
  - Guatemala - Travel, undated (Box 1)
  - Historic Newspapers, 1955-1956 (Box 1)
  - House in Antigua; Photographs, 1940 April 25, undated (Box 1)
  - Kennedy, Robert Correspondence (Original), 1966 May-June (Box 1)
  - Latin American Countries Chronology, 1956-1966 (Box 1)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Gold Medal, 1947-1963 (Box 2)
  - Maps, 1931-1946, undated (Box 2)
  - Newsweek, 1958-1966 (Box 2)
  - New York Times, 1912-1950 (Box 2)
  - Nicaragua - Quake, 1931-1938, undated (Box 2)
  - Overseas Press Club; Photographs, 1949-1957 (Box 2)
  - Pan American Highway; Photographs, 1941 May 22, undated (Box 2)
  - Panama - Background; Politics; Clippings; Correspondence; Daily Reports; Photographs, Treaty, 1907-1979 (Box 2)
  - Panama Canal Zone, 1944-1953 (Box 2)
  - Peru, 1947-1949 (Box 2)
  - The Reporter, 1953-1955 (Box 2)
  - Retirement - New York Times, 1953, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Rodezno - Salvador, 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - Travel Editor; Photographs, 1939-1941, undated (Box 2)
  - U.S. Politics, 1952 July-September (Box 2)
- Printed Material
  - Pamphlets, 1923-1964 (Box 3)
  - Books
    - The Odyssey of a Calhoun Family: From Scotland to Panama by Brittmarie Janson Perez, 2021 (Box 3 and Digital, Folder ahcdm_05607_002)
    - Our Faith moved Mountains!, 1944 (Box 3)
    - The Panama Guide, undated (Box 3)
    - Panama y su separación de Colombia, 1972 (Box 3)
    - Rails Across Panama, 1967 (Box 3)
    - Society of the Chagres: Builders of the Panama Canal, 1913,1917 (Box 3)
    - Teoría Y Práctica de la Democracia, 1955-1960 (Box 3)
    - The University Club of the Isthmus of Panama, 1915 (Box 3)
    - The United Fruit Company in Latin America, 1958 (Box 3)
- Scrapbooks and Newspaper Clippings
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1947-1978, undated (Box 3)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Columbia, 1934-1942 (Box 4)
    - Costa Rica, 1934-1941 (Box 4)
    - Ecuador, 1935-1942 (Box 4)
    - El Salvador, 1934-1947 (Box 4)
    - Honduras, 1942-1943 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous - Clippings, Letters, and Photographs, 1909-1968 (Box 5)
    - Panama, 1935-1941 (Box 4)